# Justin Graber

# Software Developer

### **Justin Graber**

Olathe Kansas

http://github.com/jpg013

(816) 588 - 9860

I work as a full-stack software developer with over 8 years of experience building and maintaining web applications. I have a passion for solving fun and challenging problems and enjoy learning new technology. My skill set includes extensive experience using React / Redux, Redux-Saga, AngularJS, RxJS, NodeJS, GraphQL, MongoDB, Elasticsearch and several other technologies. I earned a Bachelor's degree in Physics and a minor in Mathematics and I am also currently seeking a Master's degree in Computer Science with an emphasis on Machine Learning and Data Science.

# Skills

Databases: MySQL, Mongo, Redis, Elasticsearch

Programming Languages: Javascript, Node.js, Python, Golang

Frameworks: React, Redux, Angular, jQuery, Backbone

Libraries: Gulp, Grunt, Webpack, Lodash, Immutable.js RxJS, Redux, D3, Express

Web Development: Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, SVG, WebGL

APIs: Rest, GraphQL

DevOps: Docker, AWS, Bash, Linux

VCS: Git

# **Experience**

## Dunami, LLC / Presentation Team Lead

September 2015 - PRESENT, Overland Park Kansas

At Dunami, I work as the lead developer for the presentation team, which is responsible for building and maintaining all the user-facing applications as well as the API's that support the data needs of those applications. Specifically, we have built and maintained several single page applications written in React and Angular and a variety of Node.js services that provide the data contracts for these applications.

- As the presentation team lead, I manage other team members and develop / implement the front-end architecture for several large single page applications.
- I've worked as a frontend engineer to develop highly sophisticated web applications using Angular JS and React/Redux.
- I was responsible for building multiple interactive data visualizations using CSS, HTML5, and D3.
- I was responsible for developing our GraphQL api in Node.js.
- I worked with my other team members to develop a Node.js microservice architecture to serve the data contracts for our single page applications.
- I developed / publish / maintained multiple NPM modules for collaborative

use around our organization.

# Keyhole Software / Software Developer

June 2014 - September 2015, Overland Park Kansas

During my time at Keyhole Software, I worked for several clients as a full stack web application developer. I participated in developer cutting edge applications using Node.js, Backbone JS, Angular JS, Mongo, Redis and Socket.io.

- Planned, architected and developed multiple web applications with diverse stack requirements and client expectations.
- Owned several JavaScript single-page web applications using different front-end frameworks.
- Developed and maintained highly-performant RESTful APIs with Node.js.
- Worked as a technical architect to oversee the implementation of reference architecture for multiple teams.

# Ad Astra Information Systems / Software Developer

June 2012 - April 2014, Overland Park Kansas

- Developed high quality code in a professional environment.
- Worked to enhance the design and functionality of a web based, Single-Page Application using JavaScript and Ext JS.
- Worked to improve stability and performance in sophisticated back-end systems.
- Contributed extensively to refactoring database systems and SQL stored procedures for performance increases.
- Collaborated with developers and product managers to provide creative and innovative solutions for clients.
- Assisted in research project for conversion of Ext JS 3.x to Ext JS 4.x.

#### Education

**University of Kansas** / Master of Science in Computer Engineering (did not complete)

August 2011 - May 2013, Lawrence Kansas

Missouri State University / Bachelor of Science in Engineering Physics

August 2008 - December 2019, Springfield Missouri